翻译：xiaochi@China 个人爱好作品，谢绝商业应用或剽窃抄袭
合成：枪炮与玫瑰
片名：《赤焰战场2》
- Baby, check this out. - A power washer?
宝贝，瞧这儿  - 哈，高档扫地机？
We need one of these.
我们正需要这东西
Yeah.
是啊
- On the patio in the backyard. - Yeah.
在后院的露台上用得着   说的是
Should we go look at those window treatments?
我们要不要再去看下那些洗窗器？
No.
不要
Do you want one of these hotdogs?
你想不想买一个这里的热狗？
They're very good.
它们可好吃了
Baby, you are a heck of a homemaker.
宝贝，你真是个模范家庭煮男
You know that? But we could just go to dinner.
你也知道这一点对吧？不过我们也不妨出去下个馆子
Well, you know,
嗯，要我说，
if you don't make it...
自己动手...
You don't eat it.
丰衣足食
You know what? That's a great idea. What if I make you dinner?
你说呢？这是个好主意  这次我来做饭怎样？
I'm gonna go and get that, uh, grill. The big shiny one.
我去买那个，呃，烤架 买个又大又靓的
Will you get us some shrimp? The big jumbo kind.
你去买些虾怎样？要买那种又大又肥的
Four down. Three over.
往那走三、四格就是
Come back and find me down here. In tools.
回头到这边来找我 工具区
What the hell are you doing here?
见鬼你跑这儿来干嘛？
You ignored my messages.
你不回我的短信
I am happy.
我在享受幸福呢
You're desperate.
你在滑入绝望深渊
- I can make this work. - Frank, you're playing house.
我能过上正常人的生活  弗兰克，你这是在过家家
Look, I'm retired, okay. I'm happy. We are happy.
听着，我已经退休了好吧？ 我很幸福 我们很幸福
Frank... Frank...
弗兰克... 弗兰克...
You haven't killed anybody in months.
你都几个月没杀人了
That is not a bad thing, okay?
那也不是什么坏事，对不？
That's a positive thing for a lot of people.
对很多人来说都是大好事
Kemosabe, I need you. They're coming. I can feel it.
兄弟，你得帮我，他们要来了，我感觉到了
You are driving me nuts, Marvin.
你一边凉快去吧，马文
Listen, if it makes you feel better, bring the girl.
这么着，要是你高兴，带上你那姑娘
I'm not gonna bring the girl anywhere, all right?
我不会带我那姑娘去任何地方，懂吗？
Don't bring the girl where?
不会带姑娘去哪儿？
Oh, we're just catching up.
哦，我们只是偶遇
Marvin's here. I just bumped into Marvin.
马文来了 我只是恰好碰上马文
Where are we going?
我们要去哪里？
No, come on. They're gonna close.
不，走吧 这里快打烊了
Good to see you, Marvin.
再见，马文
- Good to see you. - Frank.
再见了  弗兰克
You know you want to.
你清楚自己想要去
- No. - Come on.
没有 走吧
Last chance, Frank.
最后的机会，弗兰克
I'm taking Sarah home.
我正要跟莎拉回家
Stay safe.
保重
- Well, I really wanted to be... - Of course, it is. honey.
哎，我真的很想去...当然啦，说的没错，亲爱的
You are never gonna be in danger ever again.
你可不能再经历什么危险
We don't even know what happened.
我们不清楚究竟发生了什么
We don't know who's in there.
我们都不知道那车里的是谁
How am I gonna protect you?
我该怎么保护你的安全？
Hey. He was your best friend.
嘿 他是你最好的朋友
Okay?
对吗?
Come on.
来吧
Wow.
哇
He still looks so lifelike.
他看上去栩栩如生
He's not dead.
他没死
Honey, don't do that. Just let your feelings out. Don't...
亲亲，别这样 哭出来就好了，别...
No. Really.
不 我说真的
He does this a lot.
他这么干已经很多次了
Really?
来真的啊?
No, come on. Give me the pin. Give me the pin.
不行，别这样 把针给我 把针给我
Come on, sweetie. Let's go sit down. Come on.
来吧，亲爱的 先坐下吧 来吧
- Come on. - I should kiss him.
- 来吧 - 我应该跟他吻别
Yeah, go ahead. Do you want to?
好啊，去吻吧，你想要这么做么？
Let's go sit down. Come on. Come on, sweetie.
我们找个位置坐吧 来，来，亲爱的
At this time, we'll open the floor to anyone
此时此刻，我们欢迎某位来宾
who wishes to say a few words about the deceased.
上来为死者做诀别之言
Babe...
宝贝你应该去...
Share a memory, perhaps?
也许，分享一段回忆？
Perhaps, a poem. A song lyric.
也许，一首哀诗 或是一曲悲歌
Anyone?
哪一位愿意来呢？
You can do it.
只有你能胜任此事
Sir?
这位先生？
Marvin was
马文曾是个...
different.
与众不同的人
He was
他还是...
a very good shot.
一位出色的枪手
Some would say that
有的人恐怕会指责
he was paranoid.
他是个妄想狂
But you have to expect a little of that when the CIA's dosing you with LSD
可是他不得不如此 因为中央情报局对他使用了毒品
for a little more than a decade.
折磨了他不下十年
He could wire a bomb
他拆弹的速度
faster than anybody I ever met.
是我认识的人里最快的
The good people of Moldova will always
摩尔多瓦的老百姓将因为这一点
be in Marvin's debt.
对他感恩戴德
He was a really good friend.
他是个真诚的好友
Really good.
真诚如一
I'm gonna miss him.
我会怀念他的
Gonna miss him.
深深地怀念他
- We have to move. - Canada?
- 我们得跑路了 - 去加拿大么？
High ground. Good kill zones. It's a little farm.
高地，好杀区，是个小农场
- A farm? Like, to farm on? - Yeah. Yeah.
农场？就是，种田的那种？是的，没错
Like, with crops?
就是，有很多庄稼的那种？
Yeah. It could be fun.
对 那里可好玩了
Listen, babe...
听我说，宝贝...
You know they say it's really important not to make big...
经历了悲欢离合之后...
life-altering decisions right after a loss.
不要轻率地改变自己的人生
If they can get to Marvin, they can get to you and they can get to me.
如果他们能干掉马文,他们就也能干掉你，还有我
Who are they?
他们是什么人？
Go 10 the safe house.
去避难点
Look at me. Go to the safe house.
看着我 快去避难点
I'll come find you, okay?
我会去找你的，明白吗？
- I'm not leaving you. - Listen...
- 我不要离开你 - 听话...
It'll be all right.
没事的
What is it?
什么事？
Mr. Moses...
摩西先生...
They want to debrief you at a Yankee White facility.
上面要求你去一处秘密调查点做汇报
Is that your sniper?
那边是你们的阻击手？
You're flagged Retired Extremely Dangerous.
你是被标记为“高度危险退役人员”的人
（海军罪案调查处）
Hi, there.
嗨，你好
Um, my client Frank Moses is here.
嗯，我的客户弗兰克·摩西在这里
He's an American citizen being detained illegally without due process.
他是一位被非法拘押的美国公民，未经任何合法手续
- You know what? That is a lovely blazer. - Oh, thank you.
-  你知道吗？你的运动衣真好看 - 哦，谢谢夸奖
You're welcome.
不客气
I'm sorry, I have no idea.
很抱歉，我根本不知道这件事
But let me get Mr. Snyder for you.
不过我可以帮你找下史奈德先生
Thank you.
谢谢你
How can I help you?
您有什么事吗？
- Oh, hi, there. I'm sorry. What is your name?
哦，你好 对不起 你叫什么？
- John Snyder.
John. You know what? I didn't get your name.
- 约翰 - 不好意思，我还不知道你的名字呢
- Oh, it's Kelly. - Hi, Kelly.
- 哦，我叫凯莉 - 嗨，凯莉
John...
约翰...
John... John!
约翰... 约翰！
Unless you want to end up like Kelly,
如果你不想跟凯莉一样
I suggest you tell me where Frank Moses is right now.
建议你立即告诉我弗兰克·摩西在哪儿
Now!
马上！
In interrogation.
他在审问间
Ah!
I got a document right here that says that you have a special interest in the Cold War.
我这儿有一份文档，上面说，冷战期间你有个很特别的爱好
We know that back in the day, you spent an awful lotta time in Russia.
我们知道在那段时间里，你在俄罗斯度过了一段相当漫长的时光
I just need to know what you know about Project Nightshade.
我只是想了解你对“夜暮”计划知道多少
I really don't know anything about it.
我是一点儿都不知道
What the hell is that?
出了什么鬼事情？
Small arms gunfire, 200 yards.
轻型武器开火的声音，距离200码
Watch him.
看住他
100 yards.
100码了
They're coming to kill us.
他们想要杀掉我们
Get me outta these cuffs.
给我解开手铐
I can't do that, sir.
我不能那么做，先生
You have the key, right?
你有钥匙，对不？
Hands up!
举起手来！
50 feet.
50码
They're gonna kill us both, if you don't get me outta these cuffs.
他们会杀光我们，如果你不松开手铐
Come on.
快点
Frank Moses.
弗兰克·摩西
You know, coming up through the ranks, you were my hero.
出身行伍的你，可是我心目中的英雄
Given enough time, I guess everyone cracks.
可毕竟岁月不饶人
Huh, Frank?
哼，弗兰克？
- Who are you? - Me?
- 你谁啊？ - 我吗？
Mmm-hmm.
I'm the guy the government hires to get information.
我是个给政府部门收集信息的跟班
And I'm allowed to use any form of torture I deem fit.
我被允许可以使用任何我中意的折磨手段
And I will torture Sarah until you speak.
我会折磨莎拉，直到你招供
Speaking of Sarah, I love watching her
说到莎拉，我就爱看她在浴缸里
shave her legs in the tub.
给自己剃腿毛的样子
Kinda reminds me of these Belgian mercs I met in the Congo.
让我回想起在刚果认识的，那些比利时佣兵们
They would skin people alive to get them to talk.
他们用活剥人皮来逼问口供
And do you know where they started?
你知道他们从哪里开始剥吗？
Guess.
猜猜
At the ankles. Just like your Sarah.
从脚踝开始，就和你的莎拉一样
So...
好了...
You either give me the information that I need to know...
要么你给我招供，交出我需要的所有信息...
Or I'm gonna fillet your girl from head to toe with no mercy.
要么我就把你那姑娘从头到脚，切得一片片的
Awesome.
混蛋
Wow.
哇
Pretty good for a retired guy. But are you...
对退休老头来说这招还挺厉害的 可是你真打算...
1-2-3-4-5-6. ..
1-2-3-4-5-6...
7-on-1 cuffed with no weapon good?
戴着手铐玩徒手7对1？
Son of a...
这混蛋...
Go. Go, go, go!
上上上，上啊！
Shoot him, but don't kill him.
可以开枪，但别打死他
All right, kill him. Spray it up.
好吧，杀了他 站成扫射队形
Frank, this is your last chance.
弗兰克，这是你最后的活命机会
Fire.
开火
Get in there! Go!
都进去！上！
Shit.
见鬼
Marvin!
马文！
- You're driving me crazy! - I brought the key.
你要玩死我啊   我带了“钥匙”
You faked your death.
你又装死了
- Gotta go. - Let's go.
- 该闪了 - 那走吧
Gotta go.
闪人喽
You have no idea what you put me through!
你看看把我连累到什么地步！
Oh! Thank God, you're okay.
哦！谢天谢地，你没事
No!
不！
- What are you doing here? - Marvin brought me. From the house.
你在这儿干什么？   马文带我来的 从避难点
Has everybody lost their mind?
大家伙都疯掉了吗？
- Marv, you don't bring a girl like that here. - I had to see if you were okay, didn't I?
马文，你不该带个姑娘到这个地方来   我得看看你是不是安然无恙，不行吗？
Honey!
甜心！
- I thought... - What?
- 我以为... - 咋了？
Remember when we had that conversation about how you were gonna lay low?
记得我们是怎么说的，关于你要怎么躲避风头？
You don't get to tell me when to lay.
我不要你来规定我什么时候该躲风头
I mean, I'm not saying that.
我是说，我不是那个意思
Stop. Just don't. Just don't... No.
停下 别这样 别...不要啊
- You're mad at me now? - You treat me like a China doll.
你生我气了？你把我看成一个脆弱的瓷娃娃
Frank, can I give you a little advice about women?
弗兰克，我能给你一点关于女人的建议吗？
No! Absolutely not!
不！绝对不要！
Listen, you gotta ask yourself,
听我说，你得扪心自问
what is a girl like that doing with a guy like you?
一个姑娘干嘛要跟你这样的家伙混在一起？
It ain't for your looks.
显然不是因为你的长相
You know, I will shoot you. I will shoot you in the liver.
瞧好了，我要给你一枪 给你一枪狠的
A, R, D, A.
A，R，D，A
Adventure, romance, danger, activities you can share as a couple.
冒险，浪漫，危险。像一对搭档一样的行动
It's about you lying to me.
来谈谈你骗我的事吧
Frank...
弗兰克...
I was very touched that you cried at my funeral.
我很感动你在我的葬礼上流泪了
That's not true.
没这回事
I didn't cry at your funeral.
我没在你的葬礼上流泪
I'm no crier.
哥是真汉子，才不会哭
Ninety-six hours ago, somebody posted a document on the Internet
96小时前，有人在互联网上发了个帖
that said you and I took part in an operation called Nightshade back in '79.
里面说你和我一同执行了1979年某个名为“夜暮”的行动
That's why you fake died?
你因为这个装的死？
Yeah. The chatter went through the roof.
对 早跑路早安全
So everybody's after you for something they think you know
这么说追杀你们的人，认为你们知道点什么
that you don't even know at all?
可你们其实啥都不知道？
Oh, my God! Spiders!
哦，老天爷！蜘蛛！
Honey, you need to go to ground and it's best I don't know where.
亲爱的，你得找地方躲起来，最好是我不知道的地方
Yeah, I'm not going anywhere.
是哦，我哪里也不去
- Cash only. No calls. No contacts. - Thanks. Look...
只用现金 别打电话，别联系我们。  谢啦 听着...
I'm not hanging out in some bunker while you slink around and save the planet
我才不要躲在哪个沙坑里，让你一个人去拼命，拯救地球
with dusky international femme fatales.
还能邂逅某些闷骚的国际荡妇
- Dusky? - Dark, smoldering.
闷骚？黑得像炭，热得像火
I know what it means, Marvin.
我知道那是什么意思，马文
It's hard to be the kinda person I have to be right now
这样我没办法行动
and do the kinda things that I'm going to have to do while you're here.
做事的时候也下不了手，因为有你在场就不行
This is gonna be good for us.
这样做对我们都好
What are we doing?
我们要怎么做？
Let's face it, Columbo, things were getting a little stale.
就这么决定吧，我的冒险家， 别再说这些陈词滥调了
Wow. Mommy just slapped Daddy at the dinner table.
哇 西风压倒了东风啊
Is there a human being in the trunk?
后备箱里有人？
Yeah.
对啊
Who is it, Marvin?
是什么人，马文？
He's a Senior Director of Military Intelligence.
是个军情局的高级主管
I've been caramelizing his onions for a couple of days.
我“腌”了他几天了
Caramelizing how?
怎么个腌法？
With three tabs of acid and a lot of rats.
用三种迷幻药和很多很多的老鼠
Dang!
天哪！
（五角大楼）
Eleven people dead. Five FBI. And the SecDef wants a briefing?
死了11个人，5个联邦探员。国防部长要求汇报？
You were brought in to contain this.
你要对这些事完全负责
Calm down.
冷静
I can't believe this is coming back on me after so many years.
简直不敢相信这么多年后我还要应付这种烂事
General, Moses and Boggs have been completely isolated.
将军，摩西和伯格斯已孤立无援
The FBI is seeking them for the murders.
联邦调查局正以谋杀罪名追捕他们
Homeland has been informed that they are officially domestic terrorists.
已向全国发布通告，官方定性他们为国内恐怖分子
Is that gonna work?
这样有用吗？
Yes.
是的
The problem is with that document surfacing on the Internet,
问题在于随着那些机密被泄漏在互联网上
all the players will be coming after Nightshade.
所有的势力都会对“夜暮”伸出黑手
It'll open the book on this.
那将引起天下大乱
I'm calling SecDef. We need to go public.
我要打给国防部长 我们要公开此事
General...
将军...
Nobody's going public.
没人会去公开
We need a new plan for Moses.
我们需要对摩西制订一个新计划
I need you to approve a specialist.
我需要你批准启用一位专员
What? CIA?
哪个山头的？中情局？
It's been tried' sir. Didn't work so well for those guys.
他们已经试过了，长官。对付这些人还不够看
Han Cho Bai. He's the best.
韩秋白，他是最佳人选
Do it.
干吧
（香港）
Suit, too.
衣服，也要
Okay, he's clean.
好了，他没问题
Seriously?
不开玩笑？
Sit down, Mr. Han.
坐下，韩先生
Your security is impressive.
你的安保很出色
A business associate.
一个生意伙伴
Julio Alvarez Fernandes.
胡里奥·阿尔瓦雷斯·费尔南德斯
Very diff cult to get close to.
很难接近他
Of course, it must appear like an accident.
当然，必须做得像一场意外事故
Not a problem. Except for one thing.
没问题 除了一件事
Mmm?
嗯？
Mr. Fernandes pays better.
费尔南德斯先生出的价更高
HAN; Yeah?
是？
Who's the target?
目标是谁？
Oh, it's an old pal of yours. Frank Moses.
哦，是你的一个老伙计 弗兰克·摩西
Karma's a bitch, Frank.
你的报应来了，弗兰克
（伦敦-军情六处）
What is this?
出什么事了？
There's a watchword ﬂag on a WikiLeaks document.
在一份网络泄漏的文档里 出现了一个敏感词
It's coded Priority One Alpha Seven.
被编码为 1-A-7 级
- Something called Nightshade. - Shut up!
某个被称为“夜暮”的东西  - 闭嘴！
Get out.
你出去
Find me Victoria Winslow.
给我找到维多利亚·温斯洛
Director Philips?
菲利普主管？
Um...
呃...
I'm with someone right now.
我正陪着某个人呢
Keeping busy, I see.
我看你一直很忙吧
Idle hands do the Devil's work.
下雨天打孩子，闲着也是闲着
Yes.
说的也是
I understand you can get close to Frank Moses.
我明白你跟弗兰克·摩西很熟稔
Yes.
是的
MI6 has a job for you.
军情6处有个工作给你
If you want to stay alive, you're going to accept it.
你如果不想死的话，就接受它
It's time to choose sides, Victoria.
你得选边站队了，维多利亚
Where do they teach you guys this stuff?
他们在哪儿教会你们这些的？
Manuals, mostly.
自学成才，大部分是
Mmm.
嗯
Some of this stuff you just can't teach.
有些事光靠教是教不会的
Wow.
哇
Isn't this cool?
这样不是很酷吗？
We're on a mission together.
我们一起出任务
Do you have any idea how many people are trying to kill us right now?
你知不知道现在有多少人想要来杀掉我们？
You and I both know that this is where you belong.
你我心里都明白这才是你的生活
Right here. In the thick of it.
就是这样 像走刀口一样
Pussy Cat's right, Frank.
你的小娘子没说错，弗兰克
Here we go.
我们走
Watch your step.
注意脚下
What?
这什么？
Oh.
哦
Come on!
拜托！
- Where did you get this? - Um... Marvin.
你哪儿来的这东西？呃... 马文
- You gave her a gun? - ll is America, Frank.
你给她一把枪？这儿可是美国，弗兰克
Everyone else has a gun.
人人都有枪
She has no idea what to do with this.
她根本不知道该用它来做什么
I know exactly what to do with it.
我当然知道该用它来做什么
Ow!
嗷！
You don't give fire to a kitten.
别教小猫去玩火
Why don't you just give her some dynamite, Marvin?
你何不干脆给她一些炸药呢，马文？
No external safety on the Sig?
西格手枪上没有额外的保险开关吗？
Tell him what you told me.
再交待一遍
At the height of the Cold War,
Nightshade was cooked up by a rogue US general
“夜暮”是由某个叛变的美国将军炮制的
as a first strike capability against the Soviets.
用来对抗苏联的先发攻击能力
- That's it. Can I go? - That's it?
- 就这些 我能走了吗？ - 就这么点？
- You want a little pepper with that? - No, okay! At the height of the Cold War,
还想要我再给你洒点胡椒面是怎么着？不要，好吧！在冷战的高峰时期
a megaton-yield device was smuggled into Moscow
某件大规模杀伤武器通过外交邮包
in diplomatic pouches, piece by piece, and then the weapon was lost. That's it.
以零件形式偷运进了莫斯科。然后那武器就丢失了 就是这样
You lost a nuke in Moscow?
你们在莫斯科丢了一件核武器？
The scientist was Edward Bailey. That's it.
设计者是爱德华·贝利 就这些
What?
什么？
I made a mistake.
是我的错
Edward Bailey was a genius physicist who built some of the greatest stuff
爱德华·贝利是一个天才物理学家，在冷战期间制造了
during the Cold War.
一些极其强大的东西
Neutron bombs, particle beam weapons, nerve gas. Excellent nerve gas.
中子弹，粒子投射武器，神经毒气。超级完美的神经毒气
He was a rock star of conceptual mass killing.
他是大规模杀伤武器界的摇滚明星
They called him "The Da Vinci of Death."
有个外号叫“死神达芬奇”
We were the security detail assigned to getting him in and out of Moscow safely.
我们曾执行过某项机密任务，负责护送他安全进入和离开莫斯科
What happened?
发生了什么事？
We thought he was secure. The Soviets got him with a car bomb.
我们以为他很安全。苏联人用汽车炸弹干掉了他
It was my fault.
那是我的失误
He's dead.
他已经死了
Run or fight?
逃亡还是还击？
All we've got is this WikiLeaks page off the Internet.
我们现在只有这个，从互联网上泄漏出来的文档页面
Out of a Paris IP.
来自巴黎的一个IP地址
Hmm. Paris could be anybody.
唔 可能是巴黎的任何人
Wait. Wait. Scroll back down for a second.
等下，等下 往回翻一点
- What is that? - Oh.
- 那是什么？ - 哦
Uh...
嗯...
Coffee stain?
咖啡印渍？
Mmm. Wine.
嗯 或是酒水印渍
Frog.
是青蛙
What?
啥？
We're okay.
没事
Your number.
打给你的
Yeah.
MIG has just given me a contract to kill you.
军情6处给了我个活，要杀掉你们
Apparently, you're guilty of nuclear terrorism, murder,
给你们定的罪名是涉核恐怖行为，谋杀
and you're number one on Interpol's Most Wanted.
你们也上了国际刑警的头号通缉名单
What did you say?
那你怎么说的？
Oh, I said "Yes."
哦，我说“好的”
You know, the money's good.
你会理解的，因为酬金实在很高
And anyway, if I don't do it, somebody else will.
再说了，就算我不干，也会有别人来干
Oh, and you should know the Americans are sending someone also.
哦，还有件事你该知道，美国佬也派出了某个人
Who?
谁？
Han.
韩
It's bad, isn't it?
事情不妙了，对不？
- Is that Marvin? - Yes. And Sarah.
刚才是马文在说话？是 还有莎拉
Aw! Send them my love, will you?
啊！帮我问候他们，好吗？
They're driving me crazy.
他们要把我弄疯了
Marvin gave her a gun.
马文给了她一把枪
- Was it loaded? - Yes! Yes!
上了膛的？对啊！对啊！
Are you being controlling?
你是不是控制狂？
No!
不是！
You have to take chances in a relationship.
恋爱就是这样
You have to be supportive.
你得学会支持和妥协
I don't need her to fit in. I just need her to be safe.
我不想让她过这种日子 我希望确保她的安全
Just rent Dirty Dancing, tell her you love her.
去跳个贴面舞吧，告诉她你爱她
You know' it's important to enjoy life while you still can.
重要的是享受生活，趁你们现在都还活着
Victoria just accepted a contract from MI6 to kill all three of us.
维多利亚刚接了军情6处的活，要杀掉我们仨
You don't think she'd do that, do you? Frank, you don't think she'd do that?
你不会觉得她是来真的吧，是吗？弗兰克，你不会觉得她来真的吧？
She's a friend.
她是咱们的朋友
Frank, what, are you stupid? You never took a contract out to kill a friend?
弗兰克，你犯什么傻？你就从来没接过活去杀掉一个朋友？
She called to give us fair warning.
她打电话来警告我们只是为了显示公平
Come on. There's one more thing.
走吧 还有一件事
Han just went number one.
韩已经来抢头一名了
Why don't they just dip our balls in honey
他们干嘛不干脆把 我们的卵子用蜜糖洗洗干净
and stake us to an ant farm?
然后把大伙钉在一个蚁穴上拉倒？
Come on.
走吧
Whoa! Crazy old bastard.
哇啊！混蛋疯老头
Frank, do you feel old?
弗兰克，你觉得自己老了吗？
- Not really. - Me neither.
- 不觉得 - 我也是
I mean, crazy sometimes, I guess.
我觉得，就是有时挺疯疯癫癫的
Who's Han?
韩是什么人？
Korean. Counter-intel.
棒子 反情报部门的
Frank put him in jail for a few years.
弗兰克把他送进了牢里蹲了几年
We should be super-scared of him, huh?
我们应该高度提防他，是吗？
Yes. He is the best contract killer in the world.
是的 他是世上最强的职业杀手
I've got a hit off an old alias, silent for almost 20 years.
我截获到一个很古老的假身份，沉寂了差不多20年了
He's dodging watch lists.
他是想避开监视名单
Bingo. Private ﬂight to Paris scheduled for 0900 out of Teterboro.
搞定 乘坐私人航班飞往巴黎。起飞时间定于09：00，蒂特波罗机场
Find their hotel. Get blueprints and workups on the day and night managers.
找到他们的旅馆，把建筑蓝图弄到手，还有旅馆日班，夜班的时间表
Have Vance meet us on the ground.
让万斯在当地和我们碰头
（蒂特波罗，新泽西）
They're one floor down. Two adjoining rooms. Surveillance is almost up and running.
他们住在楼下一层 两个相邻的房间。安保监视网络已经被我们入侵
This is going to be easier than I thought.
比我想象的要容易得多
Hello. Speaking.
你好 请讲
Yes.
是的
- Where are they? - They were here.
- 他们在哪里？ - 他们刚才还在这里
They ordered room service at 1:00.
他们还预约了1点钟的客房服务
What do you mean, "The plane is prepped"?
“飞机准备起飞”？你什么意思？
I think someone stole your plane.
我觉得有人偷走了你的飞机
I'm really going to enjoy killing him.
我要好好地享受他的死刑
Get me a gun that really hurts.
给我找一把打人最疼的枪来
So how good is this guy?
这家伙有那么厉害吗？
Han is the best contract killer in the world.
他是世上最好的职业杀手
Let's just say that Frank is in some very, very deep dog doo.
让我们这么说吧，你的弗兰克，现在踩进了一摊又大又深的狗屎
- He's not gonna kill me. - Yeah.
他不会杀我的。是哦
- Nobody kills Frank Moses. - Right!
- 没人能杀掉弗兰克·摩西 - 那是！
The people he really doesn't like, he tortures for a long time first.
对于他不喜欢的人，他会先用酷刑折磨很长一段时间
Can we just focus on trying to catch The Frog?
咱们还是先想想逮青蛙的事吧？
Okay. What's the action plan for target acquisition and rendition?
好啊 对于目标采集和引渡行动，我们应该制定什么样的行动计划？
Marvin?
马文？
Quit teaching her stuff!
别再教她这些术语了！
Nice.
好极
What do you think the most expensive bottle of wine in the world costs?
你知道世界上卖得最贵的葡萄酒是哪一种？
Chateau d'Yquem 1847.
法国吕萨吕斯酒庄，1847年份
Maybe five, six, maybe, bottles left in the world. It's pretty pricey.
世间仅存大概只有5瓶，要么是6瓶。那真是相当昂贵
Maybe we should get a bottle of that wine and try to catch The Frog with it.
我们也许应该去弄来这么一瓶酒，用它来逮到青蛙
（巴黎）
My God, this is so romantic!
我的天，这太浪漫了！
Come here. Keep your head down.
这边走 低下头
But we have to go to the Ile Saint-Louis for gelato.
我们得去圣路易岛尝尝那儿的冰激凌
I don't think so.
我看还是不要了
Really? What about the...
真不去？那就去那个...
- Frank, is that... - Mmm-hmm.
- 弗兰克，那是... - 嗯哼
Hello, Frank.
你好，弗兰克
- Have you seen her since? - Nope.
你找过她了？没有
God, I've missed you.
老天爷，我想死你了
Who is she?
她是谁？
Trouble.
麻烦
How are things?
过得怎么样？
Yeah, Frank, how are things?
是啊，弗兰克，过得怎么样？
Sarah...
莎拉...
This is Katja.
这位是卡嘉
Yeah. Hi.
是吧，嗨
I need to speak with you. Immediately.
我要和你谈谈，马上
What the hell was that?
什么乱七八糟的？
Katja Petrokovich. Russian Counter-Intelligence.
卡嘉·帕加威克 俄罗斯反情报部门
I think we should hear what she has to say.
我觉得我们应该去听听她会说什么
MARVIN; Frank...
弗兰克...
You don't know the half of it. She and Frank were young.
你只知其一不知其二。她和弗兰克年轻时有过交往
And he didn't have the slightest idea she was working for the Russians.
而他都不在乎，她效力于俄罗斯
She's Frank Moses' kryptonite.
她就是弗兰克·摩西的天生克星
I like you with no hair, Frank.
我喜欢你光头的样子，弗兰克
Bald men are so sexy. Virile.
光头佬最性感，充满男人味
Wow.
哇哦
She's cute.
她挺可爱的
Where did you find her? Nebraska?
你在哪儿碰上她的？ 内布拉斯达那个乡下地方？
- Kansas. - Kansas.
堪萨斯。堪萨斯
So what was it you wanted to talk to me about?
你想找我谈些什么？
I would like to believe that the US didn't plant
我本来愿意相信美国没有在莫斯科
a weapon of mass-destruction in Moscow. But I don't.
安置一个大规模杀伤武器 可我没有
Why are you in Paris?
你为什么来巴黎？
We come every fall for Strike Season
我们每年秋天都来支持巴黎的罢工
- and for the weather. - Oh?
- 还有这儿天气不错 - 哦？
Well, the US seems to think you're nuclear terrorists.
好啊，看起来美国已认定 你们是涉核恐怖分子
Russia wants complete access.
俄罗斯希望完全掌控此事
You agree now or I'll hand you over to the US government.
你们要么现在就同意我们的监管，要么我就把你们交给美国政府
Can't we just kill her?
我们现在就干掉她吧？
Excuse me for one second. Can I talk to you?
不好意思走开一下。我能和你谈一下吗？
- What? Oh. Uh-huh. Sure thing. - Come here for a minute.
什么？哦 嗯哼 当然可以。到这边来一下
- You know, I was shocked. - I got it.
你要明白，我被惊到了，吓到了
Yeah, I know. She was kinda counting your teeth with her tongue.
是啊，我了解，她仅用舌头。就把你的牙关给撬开了
A little, yeah.
一点点，是的
Can she go now?
她现在可以走了吧？
We don't really have a choice. We need her to help us.
我们别无选择，我们需要她的帮助
I promise there is nothing between us.
我保证我和她没什么纠葛
No, sir. This guy's not giving us anything.
不，长官，这家伙没什么用
Website's been scrubbed.
那网站已经被洗干净了
NSA intercepted a dispatch to the Kremlin from Paris.
美国国家安全局拦截到了一次 克里姆林宫致巴黎的紧急通信
Moses is going after someone called "The Frog."
摩西在追踪一个代号为“青蛙”的人
The Frog.
青蛙
So they call him "The Frog" because he's French?
他外号“青蛙”是因为他是法国佬？
No.
不
No, he poisoned the water supply at KGB headquarters
不是的，是因为他在克格勃总部的供水系统里投毒
with the Amazon tree frog poison.
毒药提炼自三只亚马逊树蛙
He must have been wiping those little tree humpers for years.
为了采集这些毒液，他给那3个小家伙搓了多年的澡
Incapacitated 1,600 people and left with every secret we had.
他使1600人陷入瘫痪，然后 盗走了我们所有的机密情报
You know, the guy makes a fortune selling information.
知道吗，这家伙靠出卖情报发了大财
He knows so much even the US won't touch him.
他知道得太多以至于美国都不敢动他
The hard part is gonna be taking him alive.
最难的事是要活捉他
- Superb. - Wine is wine.
美味啊。酒再好喝，也不过是酒
I want to buy American air defense protocols.
我要买美国防空通信协议
Why is it terrorists never appreciate Burgundy?
为什么你们恐怖分子总是体会 不到勃艮第葡萄酒的伟大呢？
Look, I don't think you know
听着，我觉得你不明白
who you're dealing with.
你是跟谁打交道
Shh! Excusez-moi.
嘘！请原谅
Hmm.
哼
Confirmed. It's him. It's The Frog.
确认了 是他 他就是青蛙
Just don't look at him, right?
别看他就行了，对吗？
Well, just act natural.
对，举止要自然
And whatever you do, don't look him right in the eyes.
不管你怎么做，就是别看他的眼睛
Check.
收到
Remember, don't look right at him.
记住了，别看他的眼睛
Idiot!
你个白痴！
- Marvin, you all right? - Yeah.
- 马文，你没事吧？ - 是
All right. Get her outta here.
很好 把她带走
- When? - Now!
- 什么时候？ - 现在！
Get a car!
去弄辆车！
Is that...
那个是...
Cut them off!
拦下他们！
This is not a good idea!
这可不是什么好主意！
She's not gonna get there first!
不能让她抢在头里！
Sidewalk!
走人行道！
- Yes! - No!
- 好棒！ - 不要啊
Yes!
- 好棒！
Happy trails, bozo!
享受你的逃亡吧，笨蛋！
Don't you think we should let...
你不觉得我们应该...
Shut your pie hole, Marvin!
闭上你的鸟嘴，马文！
Don't you think we should let...
你不觉得我们应该让...
Hush!
嘘！
Incoming!
小心！
Bastard! Sidewalk!
混蛋！人行道！
What the...
怎么回...
She's fine.
她没事
Got him.
发现他了
What are you doing?
你想干嘛？
Got him.
Look! What is she doing?
瞧啊！她在干嘛？
I'm begging...
我求你了...
Yeah, yeah. I got this.
行了，行了 我能搞定
I so got this.
我说了我能搞定
I hate her so much.
我恨死她了
You're wasting your time!
你们在白费力气！
You're going to regret this more than you can possibly imagine.
你们会为此后悔的，你们绝对想象不到
Hey.
嘿
You know who we are?
知道我们是什么人吗？
Yes, of course.
是的，当然了
Tell us about Nightshade.
跟我们说说“夜暮”
You think I'm going to roll over for you hegemonic Mickey Mouse-loving Americans?
你以为我会屈服于你们那，米老鼠一样可爱的美国霸权？
Leave Mickey out of it.
别侮辱米老鼠
1947 Petrus?
1947年的柏图斯红酒？
Yes. That one's rather...
是的 这一瓶好过...
God's sake!
天杀的！
1945.
1945年的
Wait, wait, wait! That bottle...
等下，等下，等下！那一瓶...
How do we find it?
我们该怎么去找它？
Never! Nightshade was the plot of lunatics.
永远别想！夜暮是战争狂人的阴谋产物
I used to be like you. Driven by ideology and fear
我曾经是站在你们一边的。被意识形态和恐惧所驱使
with no love of what's beautiful in the world.
丝毫体会不到万物之勃勃生机
I can't trust animals like you!
我不再信任你们这些野兽！
Do what you will.
你们尽管下手吧
Death is easy.
死亡是很简单的事
It's not about the destination. It's about the journey.
跨过生命终点并不难。这段过程才是异常艰辛的
Death is an art form in Russia.
在俄罗斯，死亡已经成了一种艺术
There are so many ways to take a man to bits.
有很多方法能把一个人零割碎剐
Shall we start with a Chechen facelift? Hold him down!
我们从车臣整容术开始 摁住他！
Stop! Stop it!
住手！住手！
This is how we do it.
我们向来就这么干的
Please. You're so brave.
求求你 你是那么地勇敢
But you have to understand
可你要相信我们
we're doing this for the right reasons. And this...
我们是出于善意才行此事 还有...
This isn't worth your life.
这不值得你献出生命
You must have something to live for.
你肯定有愿意活下去的动力
Art.
艺术
Wine.
醇酒
Women?
美人？
Hey.
嘿
Help us.
帮帮我们
We need this information.
我们需要这个情报
You'll be helping us save the world. Please.
你得帮我们拯救整个世界 求你了
Mmm.
唔
You, I'll help.
你，我愿意帮
Excuse me.
请借过
Thank you.
谢谢你
And you can suck it.
而你，吃香蕉去吧
Baby? Honey?
宝贝？亲爱的？
Seriously? You hooked up with that?
说真的？你们就这点本事？
What a woman.
多厉害的女人啊
Is that the same dress?
那不是一样的衣服吗？
They look the same to you?
你觉得它们是一样的？
No one ever called me Frank Moses' kryptonite.
就没人说过我是弗兰克·摩西的命中克星
Frank's crazy about you.
弗兰克对你是痴心一片
I've never seen him afraid of anything except losing you.
我从未见过他如此害怕，怕失去你
What if I'm ruining his life?
要是他因为我而变得庸碌无为怎么办？
Frank is a very simple creature with very simple needs.
弗兰克是个很单纯的生物，欲望也很简单
Okay? It's killing,
懂吗？就是杀戮
eating,
进食
sexting,
性欲
eating...
再进食...
Killing, I guess.
再杀戮，我想是
What's your point?
你想说什么？
I can! believe you kissed The Frog.
我难以置信你居然亲了青蛙
Well, I've kissed a lotta frogs.
嗯，我以前就亲过很多青蛙
- I got something for ya. - What is it?
我有东西给你。是什么？
The key to The Frog's security deposit box.
青蛙的秘密保管箱的钥匙
- From? - Credit Lyonnais.
哪儿的？法国里昂信托银行
Baby, I have a request.
宝贝，有个事问你
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
How would you feel about going out to dinner with me tonight?
你觉得今晚跟我去吃法国大餐如何？
- Hmm. - it is Paris, after all.
- 唔 - 这儿可是巴黎
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
好啊，好啊，好啊！
Stay here. I'll be right back.
待着别动，我去看看
I need you, Frank.
我需要你，弗兰克
It's not a good time.
这会儿我没空
One of our old assets has some real information.
我们的某个内线发来重大消息
He needs to meet with us right now.
他要求立即和我们会面
Nah.
不干
Frank, what are you doing? She's kryptonite. What are you doing?
弗兰克，你想干嘛？她可是你的克星。你想干嘛？
- I'll handle it. - Are you sure?
我能处理。你确定？
Yeah.
是的
It's not okay. It's just some work. - No, it's not fun.
不是好事 就是工作 不是去找乐子
- Go. You and Svetlana, you work it out.
去吧 和你的旧情人，去忙你的吧
I promise you that I will be back in time for dinner.
我向你保证准时赶回来和你用餐
I'll be back.
我会回来的
Keep her safe.
保护好她
What happened to us, Frank?
我们以前怎么分的手，弗兰克？
- Well... - Hmm.
- 这个嘛... - 嗯？
You betrayed me.
你背叛了我
You set me up. Tried to kill me.
你摆了我一道 想杀了我
I tried to kill you.
我也想杀了你
They were good times, weren't they?
过去的好时光啊，对吗？
You know, if you'd asked me to betray my country,
其实你清楚，只要你开口求我
you know I would have.
我愿意为你背叛自己的国家
Yes, madam.
- 好的，女士 - 谢谢
My God.
老天爷
You know, I looked you up once.
知道吗，我曾经去找过你
You were in a bungalow in Los Angeles.
你那时住在洛杉矶的一间小屋里
There were roses out in front.
房前种满了玫瑰花
But I lost my nerve.
可我还是失去了见你的勇气
谢谢
So what do you want?
你想说什么？
It was all about work with you, Frank. Rules.
只想说说关于你的工作，规则
Not rules.
没什么规则
Right and wrong.
只有对和错
You know, it's harder for me not to follow orders.
你该明白，要我违抗命令很难
Despite my personal feelings.
尽管我出于私人感情想违抗
But feelings don't matter any more than right or wrong.
可感情无法控制对错
Orders matter.
命令可以
Orders?
命令？
Russia will handle things from here.
俄罗斯将接管此事
I'm taking the key, Frank.
我来取走那把钥匙，弗兰克
I can't let that happen.
我不会交出来的
No?
不会？
I can't feel my arms.
我的胳膊没知觉了
Enjoy Kansas.
享受你的堪萨斯小妞吧
Hmm.
哼
He's out.
他整个人都迷糊了
He might be awake.
没准他神志是清醒的，只是不会动
Oh, good. So he can feel it.
哦，太好了 那他就会感觉疼了
Did you ever, ever in your entire career let yourself get drugged?
你，你-这-辈-子。有被人下过药吗？
You still like her!
你还在喜欢她！
And now she has the key!
现在她拿到了那把钥匙！
She doesn't have the key. She has a key.
她没有拿到“那把”钥匙 她拿走的是“一把”钥匙
What?
什么？
I knew she would play him like a banjo at an Ozark hoedown.
我就知道她会耍得他团团转
So I have the key.
所以我把钥匙换掉了
Water.
水
How long was I out for?
我晕了有多久？
Some of it's his.
有些是他买的
Et tu, Marvin?
此话当真， 马文？
Style is the only constant in life, Frank.
哥也喜欢拉风有型的生活，弗兰克
We didn't come to Paris on vacation.
我们可不是来巴黎度假的
Oh. Shopping's what I thought you did in Paris
哦，我唯一能想到的事就只有
with your boyfriend's money
花男朋友的钱在巴黎血拼
while you're waiting for him
因为我要打发时间等他苏醒过来
to wake up from being taken down
然后去追捕他那个袒胸露背
by his skanky, slutty, Russian biatch ex-girlfriend.
放荡下流的俄罗斯前女友
So thanks. Thanks. Thanks for the compliment for the fur.
所以说谢啦，谢谢啦。也谢谢你对我新买的皮草的赞美
For telling me that I look nice in my dress. It makes me feel really good.
告诉我穿上这身衣服是多么美丽。这让我感觉是如此欣喜
And it makes me feel very loving towards you also.
也让我对你的爱更加深了
Why is she doing this to me?
她干嘛要这么对我？
We can get a taxi over here.
我们可以打车回去
Frank, listen, I gotta tell you something.
弗兰克，听我说，我得教你几招
You have to start to learn to share your feelings to evolve your relationship.
你得学会开始分享你的感受  来发展你们的恋情
Even if it seems uncomfortable at first.
即使一开始时感觉很不适应
Say you're pinned down in a firefight.
比方说你被困在一个火场里
If you stay where you are, you're gonna die. Okay?
要是你迟疑不决，就没命了 对不？
So, you tell me, what do you do?
那么，你说说看，自己该怎么做？
Make the run.
要有所行动
Yes. You have got to make the run to emotional safety.
对 你必须行动起来  为了感情问题的稳定
Huh.
哈
You dead yet, Moses?
你死了没，摩西？
Not yet.
还没呢
Where's my plane?
我的飞机在哪里？
In my ass!
在我的屁眼里！
- It's in an airport outside of Paris. - What are you... Shut up!
在巴黎附近的一个机场  - 你说什么呢... 闭嘴吧！
Let's get outta here.
快闪人吧
- Marvin? - Yeah?
马文？啊？
Is that a stick of dynamite in your pocket?
你口袋里不是有一枚炸弹吗？
Yeah, but I'm saving it for an emergency.
是啊，可是我是留着保命用的
Well, this is kind of an emergency, isn't it?
那个，现在就是为了保命啊，对不？
（里昂信托银行-巴黎）
The key I gave her is connected to a particularly nasty terrorist cell
我给她的那把钥匙是用来开，属于某个极端恐怖组织
and their safe deposit box.
拥有的保险箱的
The French take this kinda thing pretty seriously.
法国人对这件事也很上紧嘛
That's enough.
够了
Put me down! Put me down now!
放开我！放开我！
All right.
好吧
We gotta move quickly, Moscow will have her out within the hour.
我们得快点，莫斯科很快就会把她弄出来
For the love of Mike.
见你的鬼去吧
All right.
好了
I'm still not talking to you.
我又没和你说话
All right. This is an MIG report on Project Nightshade.
好了 这是一份军情6处 关于夜暮行动的报告
It's about the operative that placed the device.
汇报关于安放这件装置的行动的
They took him into custody and put him on ICE.
他们拘押了他，将他投入了“冰室”
What's ICE?
什么是“冰室”？
Incarcerate, Cannot Execute. Who would they keep on ICE for 32 years?
只监禁，不能处决。什么人要被监禁上32年之久？
- Come on. Gotta go. - Come on where? Oh!
- 来吧 该走了 - 去哪儿？哦！
（英格兰）
How could she have possibly found us?
她是怎么找到我们的？
'Cause I called her and told her we were coming.
因为我打电话给她，说我们要来
I wouldn't take the pressure of not knowing.
我受不了那种悬疑小说一样的压力
Why isn't she shooting at us?
她怎么还不开枪打我们呢？
That should buy us 24 hours.
这一招可以给我们争取到24小时
Hello, sweetie.
你好啊，亲爱的
You know, the next time you two make a plan like this,
我说，下次你们再安排这样的计划
you could at least let me in on it.
你至少要通知我一声
Frank, you're compromising me.
弗兰克，你这可难为我了
Who knows what some girl is gonna squeeze out of you?
谁想得到你会被个姑娘给麻翻了呢？
Where'd you get the bodies?
你从哪儿找来的这些尸体？
My freezer.
我的冷库里
Come on. Wake up.
别介 醒醒啊
Yeah?
什么事？
What the hell's going on?
事情办得怎么样了？
- Sir? - Get anything from The Frog?
长官？在青蛙那里有什么收获？
No, he took some sorta poison before we really talked.
没有，他抢先一步，服毒了
I don't think he's gonna say anything now.
我觉得他什么也不会说了
You've got to find Moses and Boggs.
你得找到摩西和伯格斯
Mmm. Mmm.
嗯 嗯
Don't worry. I'm on the trail.
别担心 我就在路上
（伦敦）
On your right, you see the famous Tower of London.
在你们的右边，是世界闻名的伦敦塔
And shortly, we'll be passing under the Tower Bridge.
很快，我们就将从塔桥下穿过
It's a fortress.
那是个要塞
It's an asylum for the criminally insane. He's in the ICE unit.
是个对犯下刑事案件的疯子的收容所。他就在那个“冰室”里
That's an MIG Alpha Level secure facility buried deep within that building.
那里可是军情6处头等安保级别，坐落于整座建筑的最深处
It's like a prison within a prison.
就像监狱里的监狱
How are we gonna get in there?
我们要怎么混进去呢？
She wants my head! She wants my head! It's a Papist plot.
她要砍我的头！她要砍我的头！这是一次天主教徒谋反
It's her. It's that bitch Mary, Queen of Scots. She wants my head.
是她，那个婊子玛丽，苏格兰女王。她要砍我的脑袋
What are you doing? No! No!
你们要干嘛？不！不！
Get me Cecil. Get me Cecil. I'm the Queen of England!
找赛西尔来，找赛西尔来，我是英格兰女王！
Don't take me to the Tower! I'll have your head for this, you bitch!
别送我去那个塔里！敢这样对我，我要砍掉你们的脑袋，婊子们！
No! No!
不要！不要！
"Uneasy lies the head that wears the crown."
既然想头戴王冠，就接受不得安眠的现实吧
They're plotting against me. All of them.
他们在阴谋推翻我，他们所有人
There's a good queen.
女王演得还真像
Stuff it, you old bat.
马上就好，你个老巫婆
Thank you.
多谢你
Not so much the "old," if you don't mind.
我也不是那么老，你别介意
I think it was really, really good.
我觉得这样真的挺好
I thought I was kind of channeling Bette Davis.
我相信我和贝蒂·戴维斯沟通良好
Good morning. Dr. Jones to see prisoner number 17, please.
早上好 琼斯医生要探望17号囚犯
Dr. Jones? Are you with MIG?
琼斯医生？你们是军情6处的吗？
Sadly, not anymore.
很不幸，不再是了
Because I don't seem to have you on my list.
因为我的名单上没有你们的名字
Bloody thing's not working. Why's that?
这鬼东西不起作用 怎么回事呢？
You're supposed to use...
你应该用...
Lay down on the ground.
趴在地上
Attaboy. On the floor.
好样的 趴下
Number 121. Oh, there it is.
121号 哦，在那边
Frank!
弗兰克！
Who are you? You're visitors? Who are you looking for?
你们是什么人？是访客吗？你们找谁？
We love having visitors, don't we, fellas?
我们很高兴有客人来，对不对，伙计们？
Dr. Bailey?
贝利博士？
Yes. Who did you expect to find here? Hmm?
是我 在这儿你们还能找谁呢？嗯？
- Sir... - What?
- 先生... - 怎么？
I saw you die.
我亲眼看见你死了
Saw me die? Who is he?
看着我死了？他是谁啊？
Frank?
是弗兰克？
Frank Moses, my dear fellow!
弗兰克·摩西，我的好伙计！
How are you, old sport? So glad to see you. So glad you came by.
你好吗，老搭档？很高兴见到你 很高兴你来看我
We've been expecting you. Haven't we, fellas?
我们一直在等你来，对不，伙计们？
My God, Frank, why are you so old? Good lord!
老天爷，弗兰克，你怎么变得这么老？
- Sir... - What?
- 先生... - 什么？
You've been locked up here for 32 years.
你已经在这里被囚禁了32年
Come on, Frankie, you've gotta be kidding me.
少来了，弗兰克，你在逗我玩
Come on, put 'em up.
别介，收起这套吧
Thirty-Mo years. How extraordinary. Who are you?
32年 真夸张 你是哪位？
Victoria.
维多利亚
Victoria! You should read this.
维多利亚！你应该读读这个
Lenin. State and Revolution. Jolly good time. Stalin got it wrong, of course.
列宁的《国家与革命》。那个欢乐的时代。当然了，给斯大林搞砸了
So where are we going, Frank? Are you taking us
我们要去哪里，弗兰克？
to the opera again tonight? Is that where we're going, Frank?
今晚你又来接我们去看歌剧吗？我们是要去那儿，弗兰克？歌剧院？
The opera? We love the opera, don't we, fellas?
我们最爱看歌剧了，对不，伙计们？
Yes, the opera and the champagne and the strawberries all 'round.
没错，歌剧和香槟酒。还有那些草莓
Sorry, my dear, what is your name again?
抱歉，亲爱的，再说一遍你的名字？
Victoria.
维多利亚
I'm sorry, it's the drugs
我很抱歉，他们一直给我吃那种药
they've been feeding me, ifs my short-term memory.
搞的我有健忘症
The drugs they've been feeding...
他们给我吃的药...
Something that's meant to keep us peaceful, I suppose,
我想，是用来让我们保持平静
or harmless!
或是不怎么伤人！
Anyway, I know it's around here somewhere,
随便了，我知道它就在这附近
but I don't know where it is.
可我找不着它了
Dr. Bailey, we need your help.
贝利博士，我们需要你的帮助
- Mmm? - Do you remember Nightshade?
唔？你还记得“夜暮”吗？
I'm sorry, I'm looking for my pipe and my St. Christopher medallion.
很抱歉，我在找我的烟斗。还有我的圣克里斯托弗奖章
Boys gave it to someone.
小孩子们把它给了那个谁
They were little boys, you see.
他们不过是些小屁孩，你瞧
Now where it's gone... It's gone somehow.
现在它会在哪儿...一定是在哪儿
Um...
呃...
Oh, shit!
哦，见鬼！
Hey, Frankie, I'm over here.
嘿，弗兰克，我在这儿
I found it. It was in my pocket the whole time.
我找到了 它一直都在我口袋里
I couldn't find my damn pipe' though. But here it is.
我就是找不着那该死的烟斗 但找到了这个
Sorry, my dear, what was the question you asked me?
抱歉，亲爱的，你问我什么来着？
Do you remember Nightshade?
你还记得“夜暮”吗？
Vaguely. It was some kind of a bomb, I believe.
有点模糊印象 它是某种炸弹，我想
Dr. Bailey, people are looking for that weapon.
贝利博士，有人在寻找这个武器
People who want to use it.
那些想要引爆它的人
Oh, dear. Yes, I do understand, of course. Believe you me.
哦，天哪 是的，我了解，当然了。我相信你
But you know, I made many things for the Americans and
可是你得了解，我为美国人。造过很多东西，还有
Nightshade turned out to be a bit of a nightmare.
夜暮已经变成了一个噩梦
It was quite different. Turned out to be too dangerous.
它变得完全不同了。变成了极度危险的武器
So naturally, they had to lock me up in this place.
所以很自然地，他们不得不 把我囚禁在这个地方
And after what they did to me, I think it's perfectly natural
他们既然这样待我，我当然也可以
I tell them all to go F off!
心安理得地跟他们说“见鬼去吧”！
MIG tried to fake Bailey's death? Why? What are they hiding?
军情6处想伪造贝利的死亡？为什么？他们想掩盖什么呢？
You're gonna have to go. You're gonna have to go find out.
你得动身了。你得发掘出真相
You know they're gonna try and kill me.
你知道他们可能会直接杀了我
- I'll call you from Russia. - Do svidanya.
- 我会从俄罗斯给你打电话 - 再见吧
Maintenance to Bridge 7.
封锁7号天桥
We got a breach in Maximum Security.
发生最高安全等级入侵事件
Secure!
安全！
All right, what's so important?
好了，什么事这么重要？
I just heard from my source at MI6 that Edward Bailey's alive and on the run.
我刚从军情6处的内线处获知，爱德华·贝利还活着，而且跑了
- That's not possible. - This is bigger than a rogue general
那不可能。这个事可比一个叛变的将军
and his unexploded ordnance. What don't I know?
和他偷藏的军火劲爆多了 还有我什么不知道的事吗？
The game has changed.
游戏的玩法变了
The things Bailey knows are too dangerous.
贝利掌握的情报太危险了
We can't let Bailey or Nightshade fall into terrorist hands, or millions will die.
我们不能让贝利或是夜暮，落入恐怖分子之手，否则将伏尸百万
Holy shit, it's real.
我的天啊，这个居然是真的
Unless we secure it, that weapon's going off in the middle of Moscow.
如果我们不能及时接管它，这武器会在莫斯科中心地带被引爆
Right now, that's our best case scenario.
就是现在，是我们最好的出场时机
（俄罗斯）
（多罗霍沃空军基地）
Guys?
小伙伴们？
Ah!
啊！
Welcome, my friends.
欢迎你们，我的朋友们
So, it is true. You're alive.
那么，这是真的 你还活着
Tell me, then, where is this device?
来，告诉我，那东西在哪儿？
Who?
谁？
Work in progress.
我们在想办法
I never thought I'd be smuggling
我可从未想过有一天
Frank Moses into the heart of Mother Russia.
我会帮助弗兰克·摩西潜入 俄罗斯母亲的心脏
Me, neither.
Oh, before I forget. Frank. Frank, a little something.
哦，差点忘了 弗兰克 一件小礼物
If you are caught or Han catches you
要是你被抓了，或是韩抓到了你
suicide pill is a much better option than what you face.
自杀药片是更好的选择，总好过将发生在你身上的事
You die with Russian smile on.
你会面带俄罗斯式的勇敢笑容死去
Good luck. Do svidanya.
祝好运，再见啦
- Mr. Bailey. - Yes, Frank?
- 贝利先生 - 是的，弗兰克？
Is there any way you could tell us where you hid the nuclear weapon?
有没有什么办法，能让你告诉我们，你把那个核武器藏在了哪里？
Look at all those cows, Frank. They're beautiful.
看看那些母牛，弗兰克，她们真是尤物
Yeah.
真的
Cows?
母牛？
Hi! Yoo noo!
嗨！哟呵！
That's not good.
不妙了
（莫斯科）
We have eyes on, Frank.
有人盯上我们了，弗兰克
Where's my plane?
我的飞机在哪？
They paid me to kill you.
他们只是付钱让我杀了你
They didn't say I had to do it all at once.
可他们没说要给你个痛快
别动！双手举过头！
我是布斯基警官 有警员受伤倒地
This is not over, Moses.
我们没完，摩西
需要医疗救护
We're not over! It's not!
我们还没完！这事没完！
别动！双手举过头！
What's wrong with him?
他什么毛病啊？
Wow.
哇
What is this place?
这是什么地方？
My first safe house.
我的第一个避难点
Untouched, since 1984. Aw!
自1984年起从未用过 喔！
Fugu poison?
河豚毒素？
Fugu poison is deadly stuff. Terrible death.
河豚毒素是极度致命的玩意 死法很可怕
This your little gizmo? XKG gas. I invented it.
这是你的防身小玩意？ X·K·G毒气，我发明的
We tried to take out old Fidel Castro in '61 in Cuba.
1961年我们在古巴曾 试着除掉老卡斯特罗
That didn't work though.
可没成功
Any tea, Frank?
有茶吗，弗兰克？
Why does Han hate you so much?
为什么韩那么恨你？
Not enough hugs as a child.
他缺乏家庭温暖，渴望得到我的父爱
Frank framed him for stealing state secrets.
弗兰克陷害他窃取了国家机密
So he went from being a highly decorated counter-intel officer
于是他摇身一变，从高高在上的反情报官员
to... ... to being a pariah.
变成了...... 一个贱民
What's ironic though, is that Frank actually created the circumstances
讽刺的是，弗兰克由此种下了祸根
for his own death.
一手造就了自己的死亡
It's poetic.
太有诗意了
I ain't dead yet.
我还没死呢
Should you eat that?
你就这么直接吃了？
Is that safe?
那个安全吗？
It's before they had that, you know, "sell by“ date stuff.
它早就过期了，就是“发售日期”提前的那套把戏
Oh.
哦
So did you get to meet Castro?
那么说你有见过卡斯特罗？
Who?
谁？
Did you get to meet Castro?
你有见过卡斯特罗？
Yes, I did, actually. About two weeks after Kennedy was assassinated.
是的，我确实见过他。大约在肯尼迪遇刺两周后
Talking of which, Frank,
说到这，弗兰克
I'm starting to remember more and more who I am
我开始回忆起越来越多关于我是谁
and who I was and the weapons I made.
我曾是什么人，还有我造过的武器
My God, it really is amazing.
我的老天爷，这真奇妙
How efficiently those boys from MIG, may God bless 'em...
那些军情6处的男孩们真能干， 愿上帝保佑他们...
But you know something, Frank?
但是你知道吗，弗兰克？
They really do throw us away. Don't they, old sport?
我们给扫地出门了，对不，老伙计？
When we're no longer convenient, I suppose.
我猜是因为我们不再有用了
As though we'd never given them the best years of our lives.
似乎我们再也不能，为他们奉上生命中最美好的部分
Bit of a joke, really.
真是个笑话
Yes, very strange.
是的，非常奇怪
Do you remember where Nightshade is?
你还记得夜暮在哪儿吗？
I'm sorry, my dear?
抱歉你说什么，亲爱的？
Do you remember where Nightshade is?
你还记得夜暮在哪儿吗？
Oh, yes.
哦，是的
Now, this feels right.
这会儿感觉没错
It's around here somewhere. I'm sure this time.
就在这儿附近 这次我肯定
Everything looks different completely.
所有东西看上去都完全不一样了
Maybe it's over here.
也许是从这边走
- It's been hours. Hours. - Yeah, this is it.
都折腾几个小时了 几个小时。对了，就是这
Here we are.
找到了
How are those Jimmy Choos working out for you?
穿这些名牌女鞋走长路的滋味怎样？
The entrance is up there.
入口就在那边
Who's Papa John?
约翰老爸是谁？
It's new.
是新开的
Entrance to what?
什么的入口？
Secret tunnels through the old catacombs.
通过古老地下墓室的秘密隧道
Brezhnev used it to sneak his mistress in.
勃列日涅夫曾用来幽会情妇
- In where? - In there.
- 在哪里？ - 在那里
The Kremlin?
克里姆林宫？
The weapon is in the Kremlin?
那武器藏在克里姆林宫里？
It's the one place they wouldn't look.
没人会想到的地方
Jesus. Do you mind keeping it warm?
老天爷 你就不能帮个忙别让它凉了？
You have no idea the damage you've done.
你根本不知道 自己捅了多大的篓子
You kept one of our own locked up for 32 years.
你们把一个自己人囚禁了32年
I have kept the world safe.
我是为了保卫世界的和平
- If that weapon falls into the wrong hands... - The weapon?
如果那武器落入坏人之手...那武器？
You haven't the slightest idea.
你还搞不清楚状况
You must let me call Moses.
你得让我打电话给摩西
He doesn't know what he's walking into.
他不知道自己将面对什么情况
You've had your chance. It's over.
你有过机会 已经结束了
I'm sorry, Victoria.
我很抱歉，维多利亚
Sorry, my ass.
抱歉你个鬼
They say you're a legend around here.
这儿的人都说你是个传奇人物
I've...
我呢...
I've never heard of you.
可从来没听说过你
Must have been a bit before my time.
肯定是因为你太古老了
Well, you've heard of me now.
好了，现在你知道我了
How is it possible they never picked up the radiation signature from that bomb?
怎么可能这么多年他们就没，注意到那炸弹发出的辐射能量？
That's the million dollar question.
这个问题值千金
Hey, gang. This is new.
嘿，伙伴们 这个也是新的
What do you think is behind that wall?
你们觉得这堵墙后面会是什么？
Um...
嗯...
I think Russians.
我觉得是老毛子
If anybody sees that hole, we're dead.
如果有人看到那个洞，我们就死定了
I'm gonna need you to help me to disarm the weapon.
我需要你帮我解除那个武器
Frank, somebody's gotta guard the door.
弗兰克，要有人来看守这扇门
- No. - But...
- 不行 - 可是...
MARVIN; You'll need this.
你会用得上这个
将军同志，这是20分钟前在红场
彻查所有房间！立即出动军队！
One more time.
再来一次
Great. Great, What does that mean?
很好 很好 那是什么意思？
"Gas leak. Maintenance is coming."
“煤气泄漏 等待维修中 ”
- Good. And then they'll move on. - And what if they don't?
很好 那样他们就会走开。要是他们不走开呢？
- Want a gun? - Yes.
- 想要一把枪吗？ - 好啊
No. No gun.
不 不能给她枪
Just don't move. You're a security guard.
只要别离开就行。你是一个卫兵
Don't smile. You can't smile.
别笑 不能笑
You just never leave your post. Okay?
“你不可擅离职守” 明白了？
FRANK; Nice.
好极
Two shots, here and here.
要开两枪，打这，和这
Drag the body in there and repeat as necessary.
把尸体拖到里面，必要时就接着杀
- No safety. - No safety.
提高警惕。提高警惕
Frank, I don't like the Kremlin so much.
弗兰克，我很不喜欢克里姆林宫
And I like being underneath it even less.
更别说不喜欢待在它的下面
Here we are.
That's great. It's just like yesterday.
太棒了，就跟昨天才离开一样没变化
There's my wrench or crow bar. Look at this.
那是我的扳手还是撬棍，瞧这个
There.
那里
Hey, look, chaps.
嘿，瞧啊，小伙子们
That's my old pipe. I knew I'd left it somewhere.
是我的老烟斗，我就知道落在哪儿了
My dear wife bought this the fifth, 1969.
我的爱妻在1969年1月5日买下了它
It was our wedding anniversary. Oh, yes! This is, um...
那天是我们的结婚纪念日。哦，对了！这个是，嗯...
This is Nightshade, by the way.
顺便说一句，这就是夜暮
There.
那个
- Is that. .. - That's Red Mercury.
那个是...那是红色水星
Red Mercury?
红色水星？
We were always told it was a Cold War myth.
我们一直都以为它只是个冷战神话
Yes, they said it couldn't be done, but I did it. See?
是的，他们都说它不可能造出来 可我做到了 瞧见没？
Frank, if that's Red Mercury, you can zip it up in a backpack
弗兰克，如果那是红色水星，你能把它打包放在一个双肩包里
and take it on the White House tour. It's undetectable.
带着它去参观白宫。这玩意免疫任何检测手段
No signature. No fallout.
没有电磁信号 没有能量辐射
This is a weapon that will entirely change
这是一件颠覆性的武器
the balance of international power overnight. Just like that.
能一夜之间打破国际力量的平衡。就是这样
We're all gonna die.
我们都要完蛋
On your knees.
都跪下
Katja.
卡嘉
No government should have this weapon.
没有任何一个政府能拥有这件武器
Not yours. And not mine.
不是你的 也不是我的
I have orders.
我听令行事
This isn't about orders. This is about right and wrong.
这无关命令与服从 这是对和错的问题
Don't.
别这样
Did you really come to see me in the States?
你真的去美国看过我了吗？
Yes.
是的
What color were the ﬂowers outside my house?
我屋子外的那些花是什么颜色的？
Yellow.
黄色
我注意到你一直站在那堵墙边
煤气泄漏，等待维修中
我是巴夏，想去喝一杯吗？
好啊？
我想你大概也注意到我了
What in the name of... Hey!
这是怎么...嘿！
What are you doing kissing this guy?
你干嘛要跟这家伙亲嘴？
I didn't wanna kill him.
我不想杀他
What kinda stupid logic is that?
这是什么鬼逻辑？
What in the Sam Hill is she doing here?
活见鬼她又怎么会来这里？
She's working with us again.
她和我们一边了
Like heck she is.
见你的鬼我才不信
Why were you kissing that guy?
你倒是说说为啥要跟那家伙亲嘴？
Kids, what happens in the Kremlin stays in the Kremlin.
孩子们，多一事不如少一事
You are gonna have to explain this to me.
回去再跟你算这笔帐
Hey, Comrades!
嘿，同志们！
Here's to more success.
大功告成
Success.
And saving the world!
还有拯救世界！
Saving the world!
拯救世界！
Na zdorovie!
好好享用
Na zdomvie!
祝你们健康…
I got this. Right back.
我接个电话 马上就回
Hey.
嘿
Where are you?
你们在哪？
Moscow.
莫斯科
He's a nutter, Francis.
他是个疯子，弗兰西斯
MI6 didn't lock him up because he created the weapon
军情6处囚禁他，并非 因为他制造了那件武器
but because he wants to see it go off.
而是因为他想要引爆它
Hello, Frank.
好啊，弗兰克
That was Victoria, wasn't it?
那是维多利亚，对不？
Telling you that I was some son of a monster
告诉你我就是一头怪兽
who once wanted to destroy the Soviet empire.
一心想要摧毁苏维埃帝国
Yeah. Very slowly.
对，慢慢转过来
That's it. Good boy.
就是这样，好孩子
Good. In you go.
很好，你先走
Marvin...
马文...
Guns down.
放下枪
Weapons down. Very slowly.
放下枪 慢慢地
You planted the thing on WikiLeaks.
是你在网络上泄漏的这个消息
Oh, yes, it was a cell phone taken from a guard.
哦，是的，是从一个 守卫那里偷来的手机
I was just itching to get my revenge on MI6, you see.
我只是迫不及待想要 好好地报复军情6处
Frank' you were absolutely marvelous the way you found The Frog.
弗兰克，你很了不起。能找到青蛙
No one else could have found him.
除了你没人能找到他
Jack?
杰克？
Sorry, Frank, I made a deal already with Mr. Horton for Red Mercury.
抱歉，弗兰克，我已经用红色水星和霍顿先生达成了交易
- Well done, Bailey. - Thanks.
- 干得漂亮，贝利 - 谢谢夸奖
Nice to see you again, Frank. Pick up the guns.
再次见到你很高兴，弗兰克。把枪都收了
Your country appreciates your sacrifice, Frank.
你的祖国衷心赞赏你的牺牲，弗兰克
But your time's up.
不过你算活到头了
Let's go.
我们走
It's time, Bailey.
是时候了，贝利
Yes, it is time.
是的，是时候了
Very Interesting.
很有趣
Rogue American agents turned nuclear terrorists kill lop Russian officer.
叛变的美国特工蜕变成涉核恐怖分子，杀害了俄罗斯高级官员
Not good.
不太妙
So long, Frank. So long, Marvin.
再见，弗兰克 再见，马文
Come on, boys, let's go.
来吧，小伙子们，我们走
Easy. Easy.
放轻松 放轻松
Oh, please, let me take that from you.
哦，请允许我帮你拿着这个
I thought we were doing the debriefing in London.
我以为我们要去伦敦做汇报
Oh, we were. But since you're such a sick, twisted bastard,
哦，我们是要去，可你是一个心理扭曲的变态老混蛋
you're going to Colorado.
所以你将会被送到科罗拉多州
There's a secret facility there, it's about a mile underground,
那里有一处秘密设施，大约在地面下一英里处
where you will spend your remaining years having every bit of knowledge
你将在那里度过余生，我们会从你那颗大脑袋里面
plucked from that giant head of yours.
榨出所有的情报
- Really? - Hmm.
- 真的？ - 唔
And since we're speaking frankly,
坦白地告诉你，和你的未来相比
I should say that it will make your last 32 years
你过去32年的囚禁生活
seem like a vacation in the Caribbean.
就像在加勒比海度假一样幸福
Cuff him.
铐上他
Mmm.
嗯
Oh, I say.
哦，我懂了
Well, well.
好啊，好啊
Bet you didn't see that coming. Did you, old man?
你可没想到这一招，对吧，老头子？
I must say, I didn't. Jolly good.
我承认，没有，很厉害
After you.
你先请
Thank you. Good morning, gentlemen.
谢谢你，早安，先生们
What did he say?
他说什么？
Ready.
“预备”
Do something. Do something.
想想办法，想想办法
I love you.
我爱你
At least Han didn't get us first.
至少没死在韩的手里
Really? You're gonna bring that up right now?
说真的？你打算这时候提起这事？
Ah, there is nothing more sexy in the whole world
啊，世界上最性感的事物
than a beautiful woman with an incredible gun.
莫过于一位美人怀抱，一把精工制作的名枪
You're such a romantic.
你可真是个浪漫种子
Watch your eyes.
小心眼睛
Close your eyes.
闭上眼
I love the way your toes curl right before you fire.
我最爱看你射击前脚趾微曲的样子
Hopeless.
真是没救了
Mmm.
唔
Ah!
啊！
- Freeze. - Shh!
- 别动 - 嘘！
You know something? I don't think you ought to point that idiotic thing at me.
你看出什么了吗？我不觉得你应该拿着那个蠢玩意儿指着我
You should really start thinking about your security protocol, don't you think?
你不过是遵从安全条例，不是吗？
What the hell is that?
那是什么鬼东西？
That, my dear boy, is an antidote
那个，我的孩子，是解毒剂
to the most powerful nerve agent ever created. Look.
用来对付最强力的神经毒气 瞧
Hello, boys.
你们好，孩子们
Hello, Mr. Davis.
你好，戴维斯先生
And you didn't see that coming.
你也没想到有这一招
Did you, old sport?
对吧，老伙计？
I'm sure you wouldn't want to miss what's coming next.
我想让你看看你的未来会是什么样
It's a little antidote. Jolly good.
这是给你的解毒剂 很有效
That's right.
好了
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
喔，喔，喔，喔
Good. Thank you.
很好 谢谢你
Jolly good.
妙哉
Honestly, two days, Frank, two days,
说真的，就2天，弗兰克
and you're in front of a firing squad?
2天而已，你们就落到面对行刑队的下场？
Yeah. But look...
是的 不过你瞧...
No. No excuses. You're better than this. It's pathetic.
不，不可原谅 你不该出这种岔子，真可悲
Frank, an American military transport made an emergency landing in London.
弗兰克，伦敦的某个美军机场发生一起迫降事件
Everyone aboard was found dead.
机上人员全部死亡
Bailey has taken refuge in the Iranian embassy.
贝利已躲入伊朗大使馆寻求避难
The Iranian embassy?
伊朗大使馆？
We've gotta go there.
我们得赶快去那里
All right. Get 'em ready.
好吧 准备起飞
I'm gonna make sure we're cleared for takeoff.
我去确保起飞前一切顺利
If the world is here in a week,
要是世界将在一周内毁灭
I will meet you in the Turks and Caicos.
我会在特克斯和凯科斯群岛等你
Mmm-hmm.
嗯哼
And we will spend all night
然后我们将携手共度漫漫长夜
- beneath the stars. Beneath the stars.
伴着漫天的灿烂星光。伴着漫天的灿烂星光
Mmm...
唔...
I don't speak Korean!
说人话！
You having fun yet?
你觉得好玩吗？
I'll let you know when I start having fun.
我觉得还没开始呢
You betrayed me.
你背叛了我
I had no choice.
我别无选择
You'd have done the same thing, if you were me.
如果你是我，也会做同样的事
How much is the US paying you?
美国政府给你多少钱？
20 million.
2千万
Are you kiddin' me?
开什么玩笑？
I asked for more.
我要的价更高
What happened to you?
你是怎么了？
You used to be a good agent.
你曾经是个很出色的特工
Stop! Wait a minute. Listen, I need your help.
住手！等一下。听着，我需要你的帮助
I know there's a part of you that wants to do the right thing.
我知道你的内心深处还是想行善的
There is a weapon that's gonna be detonated...
有个武器将要被引爆...
Bullshit.
狗屁
It's not bullshit.
不是狗屁
There's a bomb headed for London right now.
现在就有个炸弹已被运至伦敦
Eleven million people are gonna lose their lives if you don't help me.
1千1百万人将死于非命，如果你不肯帮我的话
All right.
好吧
Let's go.
我们走
This doesn't mean I'm not going to kill you later.
回头我还是要干掉你
I know.
我知道
I think the Way to make a relationship work
我觉得要让恋情保持良好
is that neither of you give up who you are. Don't you agree, Marvin?
重要的是双方都要学会改造自己。你同意吗，马文？
Exactly. Exactly what Marvin says.
完全正确 马文说的一点都不错
Falling in love is like jumping off a cliff. You just have to believe and let go.
坠入爱河就好像在悬崖上玩蹦极，你只要解放心灵，放手去做就对了
My God!
天啊！
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
No, he's all right.
不，他不要紧
He's with us.
他站在我们这边了
We talked it out.
我们做了一次友好的谈话
Kill Bailey. Secure the weapon.
干掉贝利 接管那件武器
How hard can it be?
小菜一碟
Of course, the external security is very, very heavy
当然，大使馆里里外外
but inside there are hardcore Revolutionary Guards.
都有伊朗革命卫队的精兵守护
They are serious fanatics.
他们可是极端狂热分子
The whole thing depends on her.
You do realize, if they catch you, they will kill you.
你得做好心理准备，一旦 被他们抓住就是死路一条
I know this won't be easy for you, but don't worry.
我知道你不好受，但是别担心
Okay?
好吗？
You know, I've been thinking about
你不知道，我一直在考虑
you and me.
你和我的事
And I just...
而我刚刚...
I got you something.
我有东西给你
Wow.
哇
You like it?
喜欢吗？
- I love it. - Seven rounds.
- 我爱死它了 - 装弹7发
- Okay. - Not yet. I'm not ready.
- 来了 - 不行 我还没准备好
- Stop, no. - Not right now. Wait.
别这样，不要
If you don't do it, you're gonna blow it, all right?
如果不照计划做，我们 大家都会完蛋，对吧？
Look at me.
看着我
- I'm gonna count to three. - Mmm. Listen...
- 我来数到三 - 嗯 听我说...
I'm gonna count to three, okay?
我数到三，好吗？
- We can go back to the... - In English.
我们还是先回去...
- One... - Not now. No. Wait.
1...先不要 不，等等
Two...
2...
God damn it.
天杀的
Hi.
嗨
She's gonna get killed.
她会送命的
It's tough when they leave the nest.
小鸟不再依人是不怎么令人好受
Frank, come on. A little trust.
弗兰克，得了吧 给她一点信任
She has talents you and I will never have.
她拥有你我做梦都想不到的天赋
What talents?
什么天赋？
People like her.
人见人爱
If she lives, this'll be good for your relationship.
她活着，对你的感情归宿就是好事
You're right.
你说的没错
And if there's one thing I know, it's women and covert ops.
我还知道一件事。这是美人计和伪装行动
That's two things.
你说的是两件事
No, grasshopper.
不，你个不开窍的土豪
It is not.
就是一件事
I wanna tell you a secret, Mr. Minister.
我想告诉你个秘密，部长阁下
Is she gonna make outwith this guy, too?
她是不是也要吻这个家伙了？
Ohh!
噢！
What the hell was that?
这是什么鬼东西？
Blowfish poison.
河豚毒素
Paralysis and shooting pains will grip your entire body.
麻痹和枪伤引起的痛感 会吞噬你的整个身躯
And you will slowly asphyxiate until you choke to death
然后你会缓慢地陷入窒息直至死亡
while remaining fully-conscious, unless you do exactly what I say.
同时神志却完全保持清醒，不想死得这么惨就照我说的去做
I will die before I compromise my country.
要我背叛我的祖国，我宁可去死
Okay. We will drive you to your office where you will write a letter on official stationery
好吧，我们会送你去你的办公室，你要在那儿用官方公文写一封信
denouncing the treatment of women in Iran.
公开谴责伊朗妇女所遭受的歧视
Then you will get your antidote.
然后你就能拿到解毒剂
That's it?
我还以为多大事儿呢？
（伊朗大使馆，伦敦）
How may I help you?
您有什么事吗？
我想向伊朗投诚
Ah. Dr. Bailey, my apologies for the delay.
啊 贝利博士，抱歉耽搁了这么久
Professor Dombrovski has declared the weapon authentic.
多姆布拉斯基教授已经 验证了该武器的真实性
And we're prepared to proceed.
我们可以开始启动它了
As soon as my money's transferred, Mr. Ambassador.
我的钱一到账就动手，大使阁下
Move! She's with me.
走开！她和我一起的
Arman?
阿尔曼？
He needs to go.
叫他离开
Okay, okay.
好的，好的
What are you talking about? Who is she?
你说什么？她是谁？
Sir, I'm sorry, you need 10 leave.
先生，我很抱歉，你得离开此处
You need to shut up!
你给我闭嘴！
No.
不要
What? What is happening here?
怎么了？发生了什么事？
Sorry. What are you doing?
Tell me what is happening here! Who is she?
告诉我这是怎么回事！她是什么人？
Get out! When I say "get out," gel out of here!
出去！我说“出去”，你就给我出去！
You need to go!
你得离开这里！
You shut the fuck up!
闭上你的鸟嘴！
Where's the safe?
保险箱在哪儿？
What?
什么？
Where's the safe?
保险箱在哪儿？
Poo pods coming.
一大波粑粑正在接近
24 Hour Plumbing.
24小时无休管道维修服务
Hurry. Emergency. Water everywhere. Come quick.
赶紧的 紧急情况 水漫金山啦 快点来啊
Stop! Plumbers, wait!
站住！水管工，等等！
It's okay! This way.
不要紧！这边走
Money received.
资金已到账
Good show.
好戏开场了
Let's see our friend here.
先来看看这边咱们的朋友
Would you lend me your knife, please?
能把你的刀借给我吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
Sorry about the mess on the carpet.
抱歉把地毯弄脏了
Oh, well.
哦，好了
At this point, Jack... You don't mind me calling you "Jack," I hope.
都这个时候了，杰克...希望你不会介意我亲切地称呼你“杰克”
You must be beginning to comprehend
你应该开始从上一次失败的震惊里
the stunning totality of your failure.
舒缓过来，领悟到些什么了
You can't give it to them.
你不打算把它交给他们
Oh, I've no more interest in giving Red Mercury
哦，我既不会把红色水星交给你们
to these boys than I have in giving it to you.
也更没兴趣交给这些小伙子们
Jesus.
天啊
Yes, it's a sad old world, you know.
是啊，世界在悲伤地老去，你也明白
Anyway, that's only my opinion.
随便了，我想说的就这些
But the central point is this, Jack,
不过中心思想是这个，杰克
you see, when men like you and those dickheads from MIG
瞧，比如你，和军情6处的那些鸟人
or CIA or whatever sewers you came from.
或是中央情报局，或是随便 哪个阴沟里钻出来的人渣
When you take away not only my life
你们不光消磨了我的青春
but the innocent lives of my dear beloved wife Natasha
还夺去了我无辜爱妻娜塔莎的生命
and my little boy, who was only six, you see. Yes.
还有我仅仅6岁的儿子，知道吗
I mean, what can I say?
我的意思是，我还能说什么呢？
When you mess with me, buddy,
人若犯我，伙计
this is what you get.
我必犯人
Go to hell, old man.
下地狱去吧，老家伙
Fare thee well, patriot.
永别了您哪，爱国志士
Boom.
嘭
Now what's next?
接下来该干啥？
Ah, Washington.
啊，华盛顿
Baby, hey'
宝贝，嘿
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Hah!
哈！
Awesome!
了不起！
Oh, shit.
哦，该死
- Is that it? - it's counting down, Frank.
是那个吗？它在倒计时，弗兰克
Shut it off. Right?
那就关掉它 行吗？
Shut... Yeah. With what? Acupressure?
关掉...说的轻巧 我用什么关？给它针灸吗？
- I don't know. - Well, why is it my responsibility?
我怎么知道。好嘛，为什么这成了我的份内事？
Just do something.
赶紧想想办法
With my Mr. Chemistry set?
就用我的化学试剂箱？
I don't know what I'm doing. You want me to push a button?
我不知道该怎么做。你想我随便按个按钮试试？
Bailey's loose and the bomb's ticking.
贝利行踪不明，炸弹已在倒计时
Wait. Excuse me, ma'am.
等一等 请原谅，女士
Hello, I have an appointment.
你好，我有个预约
Gun!
有枪！
Gel that bomb outta here.
把炸弹带走
- Drop it now, darling. That's right. - My gun!
把它扔了，亲爱的 这就对了。我的枪！
Press the button. Ground floor.
按那个按钮 去地面一层
Marvin, let's go!
马文，我们走！
Jolly good show.
大戏热闹开场
Bollocks.
该死
You really drive this ridiculous thing?
你就开这么个搞笑的东西出来？
Can you shoot?
你会开枪不？
We need eyes, Francis.
我们需要空中追踪，弗兰西斯
Come on, Frank. Forty minutes.
赶紧的，弗兰克 还有40分钟
Marvin, how ya doin' back there?
马文，你在后面干什么？
I can't talk to you right now.
我现在没空说话
How is it?
怎么样？
It's fine.
没事
Shit!
该死！
Show me something.
秀点能耐出来
Victoria,
维多利亚
I got eyes on. Bailey's heading for the M4.
我发现他们了 贝利正向M4行进
Got it.
收到
Got it!
找到了！
This one should stop it and this one should detonate it.
这条应该是停止，而这条应该是引爆
It's fifty-fifty, Frank.
一半对一半的机会，弗兰克
Wait!
等等！
That's weird.
奇怪了
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
你知道你自己在干什么吗？
Wait, wait! Wait!
等等，等等！等一下！
Stop cutting wires!
别再乱剪电线了！
I knew we were gonna die!
我就知道咱们全都要完蛋！
- Ready to kill this son of a bitch? Abso-bloody-lutely.
准备好干掉这个混蛋了吗？绝--对--的
Damn it!
天杀的！
Trouble.
麻烦了
Marvin!
马文！
Frank, it's two pedals and two sticks.
弗兰克，直升机有2套操纵杆和脚舵
Okay.
好吧
Damn it! We missed him. He's going into the airport.
该死！我们跟丢了 他往机场去了
Go get him!
去逮住他！
- Well, where are you? - In trouble.
- 好吧，你们在哪？ - 仆街中
Turn back! You are in restricted airspace.
掉转机头！ 你们闯入了禁飞区
Frank, they're gonna blow us outta the sky.
弗兰克，他们会在空中把我们轰成渣
I wouldn't worry about that.
我不想操心那个事
The engine's shutting down.
引擎正在停止运转
Mayday! Mayday!
呼叫救助！呼叫救助！
Frank!
弗兰克！
I knew we were gonna die!
我就知道我们全都要完蛋！
This is your last warning!
最后一次警告！
Oh, please, tell me you're not crashing with a weapon of mass destruction.
哦，拜托，别告诉我你们正带着一个大规模杀伤武器玩坠机把戏
No, Frank, no.
不，弗兰克，不要啊
Oh, God.
哦，我的天啊
You okay back there, Marvin?
你还好吗，马文？
It wasn't exactly a three-point landing, Frank.
这次着陆可真不咋样，弗兰克
How's the bomb doing?
炸弹怎样了？
I can't stop it.
我没法让它停止
We gotta get it outta here.
我们要赶紧带它离开这里
Hey! Hey!
嘿！嘿！
Get outta the car.
从车里出来
Hello, Frank.
你好，弗兰克
Welcome aboard.
欢迎登机
Always the good soldier, aren't you?
始终是个忠诚的战士，是不？
Stalemate.
现在成了僵局
How will you take him out and not shoot her first?
你该怎么只打死他而不伤到她呢？
Frank, it's okay.
弗兰克，没事的
You can shoot. It's okay.
你开枪吧 没事的
Put the gun down.
放下枪
Put the gun down!
放下枪！
Drop the gun!
把枪扔了！
Put the gun down, Frankie.
把枪放下，弗兰克
Thank you.
谢谢你
Pretty smart.
真机灵
So love does conquer all.
于是爱情战胜了一切
Go to your golden warrior.
到你的黄金圣斗士身边去吧
That's a good girl.
真是个好姑娘
Aw!
啊！
Come here.
来抱抱
Ah! It's so sweet.
啊！真甜蜜
Now leave the plane. Take Nightshade with you.
现在离开飞机，顺便带上夜暮
Bye, Frank.
再见，弗兰克
Sweet dreams.
祝好梦
Why didn't you just shoot me?
为什么你不直接开枪打我？
- What happened? - I couldn't disarm it.
怎么了？我没能拆除炸弹
Oh, crap.
哦，要死了
Marvin,
马文
it's going to detonate?
就要爆炸了吗？
Yeah.
是啊
Put your arms around me.
抱住我
Oh...
哦...
I didn't see that one coming.
我可没想到有这一招
There's something you don't see every day.
这个奇景可不是每天都能见到的
You put the bomb on the plane.
你把炸弹放到了飞机上
And, um, you didn't think to mention that?
那个，嗯，你也不准备通知咱一声？
You blew up my plane.
你居然把我的飞机给炸了
Sorry.
对不起
I was wrong? So we're not even gonna die?
我搞错了？就是说我们都不会死喽？
Not yet.
还没呢
I was actually starting to like you. I was even thinking about not killing you.
我确实开始喜欢你了。我甚至在考虑不杀你
This is what happens when you try to save the world.
就算是对你拼命拯救世界的回报
Han. Han, you can't
韩，韩，你不能
- put a price on these things. - U h-uh.
- 在这种事上也卖个价钱 - 哼哼
You owe me 30 mil for the plane. And 20 for not killing you.
你欠我3千万的飞机钱。再加上2千万的不杀之恩
You're a dead man, Moses.
你死定了，摩西
Thanks for your help.
感谢你的帮助
Really.
真心的
You think he means it?
你觉得他是说真的吗？
Nah, he's a nice guy.
才怪，他是个好人
I mean it, Frank!
我是说真的，弗兰克！
All right.
好啦好啦
Aw!
喔！
They're going to be right as rain.
他们能水乳交融真好
He made the run to emotional safety.
他是听了我的建议才行动起来
So...
嗯...
I did hear about this job in Caracas.
我听说在加拉加斯有个活儿
And?
然后呢？
Don't look at me. She's your girlfriend.
别看我，那是你的女朋友
Oh.
呃
Come on.
来吧
《赤焰战场2》
= 感谢观赏 = 翻译：xiaochi@China